<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine &amp; Deep Learning Portfolio on Jairo V.</title>
    <link>https://jairo-deep-learning.github.io/Jairo_Portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Machine &amp; Deep Learning Portfolio on Jairo V.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jairo-deep-learning.github.io/Jairo_Portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fetch_lfw_people dataset: Facial Recognition with Support Vector Machines</title>
      <link>https://jairo-deep-learning.github.io/Jairo_Portfolio/post/project-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jairo-deep-learning.github.io/Jairo_Portfolio/post/project-7/</guid>
      <description>This dataset is a collection of JPEG pictures of famous people collected over the internet, all details are available on the official website:
http://vis-www.cs.umass.edu/lfw/
The purpose in this project is to recognize the face of person in the picture and label it with its full name, based on a training process composed by thousand of labeled pictures.
For this project, all picture are black &amp;amp; white (sklearn.datasets.fetch_lfw_people &amp;ndash; parameter color = False)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cancer dataset: Breast cancer detection using knn</title>
      <link>https://jairo-deep-learning.github.io/Jairo_Portfolio/post/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jairo-deep-learning.github.io/Jairo_Portfolio/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description>K-NN is a machine learning technic used to classify data analysing similarity in features of data. In this project, K parameter was tested in several values: 3, 5, 7, 9 and 12. At the end, best performance was reached when K = 5, with a precision rate &amp;gt; 98%.
 Link to GitHub Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boston dataset: Price estimation using Regression Decision Trees and Regression Random Forest</title>
      <link>https://jairo-deep-learning.github.io/Jairo_Portfolio/post/project-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jairo-deep-learning.github.io/Jairo_Portfolio/post/project-6/</guid>
      <description>This project used Boston dataset to estimate price of houses. For this case, supervised learning technics as Regression Decision Tree and Regression Random Forest were used to evaluate data.
 Link to GitHub Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iris dataset: Species detection using Decision Trees and Randon Forest</title>
      <link>https://jairo-deep-learning.github.io/Jairo_Portfolio/post/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jairo-deep-learning.github.io/Jairo_Portfolio/post/project-5/</guid>
      <description>Species detection using Decision Trees and Random Forest technics. Iris is a very popular dataset used for accelerating learning curve in data scientists. Other machine learning technics can be run for Iris dataset, like Logistic Regression and KNN.
 Link to GitHub Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bank dataset: Predicting clients for financial services</title>
      <link>https://jairo-deep-learning.github.io/Jairo_Portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jairo-deep-learning.github.io/Jairo_Portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>Many companies directs marketing campaings to all their leads. However, the effect of this campaings could be different from one potencial customer to other. So, what if marketing teams could have the possibility to predict which customer will buy from the mass of clients???
Well, in this analysis we try to create a model that allow us to predict who is going to buy a bank service and who is not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wine dataset: Unsupervised learning for clustering wine references</title>
      <link>https://jairo-deep-learning.github.io/Jairo_Portfolio/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jairo-deep-learning.github.io/Jairo_Portfolio/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>It is well known that wine has motivated people to socialize, create, party, and adventure. It’s no wonder, billions of people around the globe identify as wine lovers!
In this dataset, we find 1600 wine references with the following features and the goal is to create clusters that group references by similarity. This way, we could classify a new wine reference, that has not been included in this analysis, in one of the clusters defined here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advertising dataset: How to predict sales based on advertising investements</title>
      <link>https://jairo-deep-learning.github.io/Jairo_Portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jairo-deep-learning.github.io/Jairo_Portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>Marketing teams usually promote their products in different kind of media. For example: TV, radio, newspaper, social media, etc. However, the impact in sales could be different for each kind of media. Perharps, investing in TV or radio would generate a bigger sales growth than investing in newspaper!! In this repository, you will find a model to predict sales based on different kind of media and also, it will help to identify which kind of advertising should be performed by the company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://jairo-deep-learning.github.io/Jairo_Portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jairo-deep-learning.github.io/Jairo_Portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>Follow me on these social media platforms.
   Platform URL     LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jairo-enrique-villamizar-vasquez-b6461276/   GitHub: https://github.com/jairo-deep-learning    You can contact me at these emails.
 jvillamizarv@yahoo.com jvillamizar@smmsas.com jvillamizarvasquez@gmail.com  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
